onemedicalpassport.com 2016-11-25

# One Medical Passport Privacy Policy

Overview

Your privacy and the security of the data you provide are of the utmost importance to us.  Because we gather medical information we feel you should fully understand the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information.  We understand your medical information is a very personal subject, and we want to make sure you are as comfortable as possible.  This privacy statement discloses what information we gather, how we use it, and how to correct or change it.  Questions regarding this statement should be directed to One Medical Passport's Support team. 

General Types of Information 

Information collected on the Internet can be categorized as either anonymous or identifiable. 

Anonymous information is information that can't be necessarily traced to a specific individual.  This type of information provides One Medical Passport with data to make the site easier to use (like what types and versions of browsers are used).  This information does not allow us to necessarily know the identity of users. 

Identifiable information is information that tells us exactly who you are or could be used to determine who you are.  Some of this information is essential for One Medical Passport to be able to protect your personal information and allow you to access it. 

Information One Medical Passport Gathers and Tracks 

Anonymous Information

The One Medical Passport web site logs IP addresses and browser information for systems administration purposes and to continually improve our web site by understanding usage patterns and where users click for assistance.  We do not link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable. 

Identifiable Information

This information is collected in one of three ways: (1) when you register as a patient, (2) when you fill out a preoperative questionnaire, and (3) when you log into Account Home or modify a preoperative questionnaire. 

Patient Registration

Upon registering as a patient on One Medical Passport, your name, address, phone number, date of birth, sex, a username, and password will be stored.  This information is needed to uniquely identify you and your preoperative questionnaires. 

Preoperative Questionnaire

Each time you fill out a preoperative questionnaire, the medical history you provide will be accessible to the doctor performing the procedure and the medical facility where the procedure is to take place. A very limited number of One Medical Passport staff may also have access to private information (see "Security Procedures in Place to Protect Information," below, for a full description). 

Logging Into Account Home or Modifying a Preoperative Questionnaire

Whenever you enter Account Home or modify a questionnaire, a log record is created for security purposes.  If, for any reason, there is a question about who is accessing information and when it was accessed, the log file can be reviewed. 

Disclosure of Your Information 

YOUR INFORMATION IS NEVER SHARED WITH ANYONE BUT YOUR DOCTOR AND ESSENTIAL MEDICAL FACILITY STAFF 

One Medical Passport will never send you a mass emailing and will only contact you to respond to a request or question.  Your information is only provided to relevant medical facility staff and doctors when you fill out a preoperative questionnaire.  A medical facility staff member may only access your preoperative questionnaire submission if the member is registered as a staff member of the medical facility where your procedure is scheduled to take place.  If you have not scheduled a procedure with a medical facility, a staff member cannot access your information.  A doctor may only access your submission if he or she is the doctor specified as performing the procedure.  A doctor may not access your record if not specified as performing the procedure.  A very limited number of One Medical Passport staff may also have access to private information (see "Security Procedures in Place to Protect Information," below, for a full description). 

Organization Collecting the Information 

When you register with One Medical Passport, the information is collected and maintained solely by One Medical Passport.  Your information is not used for mailings, or marketing.  The information you provide is only used for your scheduled preoperative visit. 

Aggregated and De-Identified Information 

One Medical Passport maintains the right to access and use patient medical information, in aggregate and de- identified, so that no patient's private information can be associated with that patient, to comply with requests for operational and statistical data. 

Cookies 

A cookie is a small data file that some web sites write to your hard drive when you visit them.  One Medical Passport uses a temporary cookie to keep your place while you are logged in, but stores no personal information on your computer.  This cookie expires after you exit One Medical Passport. 

Security Procedures in Place to Protect Information 

Technical

One Medical Passport operates a secure data network protected by an industry-standard firewall.  Our firewall acts to allow only certain types of messages to pass to and from our site.  This only allows legitimate One Medical Passport messages to be sent to our system and refuses all other messages before they can reach any sensitive information.  Our systems are also monitored 24 hours a day, 7 days a week.  This is to ensure all of the protections are functioning correctly.  We also remain up-to-date on all security advances and risks.  As a further security measure, our database is not accessible via the Internet.  All confidential information is transmitted using 256-bit SSL (secure sockets layer) encryption (Green Address Bar).  Using encryption involves 'scrambling' transmitted data, so that if a person were able to intercept the information, they would not be able to understand it.  If there are 75 or more minutes of inactivity within your session you will be required to reenter your username and password.  This protects your information while you are away from your machine. 

Patient

A username and password are required to access your information.  You are ultimately responsible for the security of your username and password.  Please take care to select a password that you don't need to write down, but that is unique.  If you do need to store your password, keep it separate from your username. 

One Medical Passport Staff

Only a very limited number of One Medical Passport employees are allowed to access personal information for the limited purposes of assisting you, your physician or medical facility staff member(s) and making our site function better.  All employees must abide by our privacy policy and any violations are subject to disciplinary action (up to and including termination).  Access to systems is restricted by using token authentication and is not accessible through the Internet. 

Correcting or Updating Your Information 

You may modify your personal information by entering Account Home from the homepage.  Once you have identified yourself by entering your username and password you may then select 'Edit your personal information' or 'Change your password'. 

Removing Yourself from One Medical Passport 

If you wish to be removed from One Medical Passport's database for any reason you may contact our Support team with your name and username.  Once we have verified your identity we will remove any existing information from our systems. 

Contacting One Medical Passport 

Should you contact us through our contact form we will contact you by the means you have specified.  We will retain your message for later referral should you ever contact us again.  Your request may also be used to determine areas of the site that may be enhanced in the future. 

External Links 

We have provided external links to other sites (such as a verifier of our 256-bit SSL certificate) that are outside our control.  If you click these links, you will enter sites that may have different privacy policies from One Medical Passport. These websites are not governed by this Privacy Policy, and we do not take responsibility for the privacy practices of any third-party websites to which we link. 

Foreign Language Support 

If a language other than English is selected by the patient the page is translated with Google Translate. The page contents are sent to Google, translated, and then returned in the specified language. Google does not log any of this text. If you are viewing the site in English, no information is sent to Google. 

Changes to our Privacy Policy 

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy. We will provide notification of the material changes to this Privacy Policy through the site. 

This policy was last modified on September 14, 2015.
